(571) 523-3345 McLean, Virginia ytyeung@gwu.edu

# Yat To Yeung, Bosco

# Quantitative Social Scientist/PhD Candidate

Website: ytyeung.com linkedin.com/in/yeung317

Dedicated and experienced researcher in Asian American identity politics and regulatory politics in Greater China. Keen to leverage quantitative and survey research skills in real-life settings and provide evidence-based solutions to drive positive change.

#### **SKILLS**

Tools and Languages

R, Stata, SQL, ŁTFX, Tableau, Qualtrics

Quantitative Research Communication

Causal Inference, Machine Learning, Surveys and Experiments (A/B Test), Data Visualization

English, Cantonese, Mandarin

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

PHD CANDIDATE

AUG 2019 — Present

George Washington University

Washington, DC

- Designed a field experiment and analyzed large survey data with 10000+ respondents to study elite and public decision making.
- Analyzed 6000+ public consultation documents in China, Hong Kong, and Taiwan to examine differences in approaches to civic engagement and regulation.
- Collaborated with 10+ researchers across multiple disciplines on projects that examines Chinese government responsiveness and online hate and anti-vaxx communities in the US.
- Lectured undergraduate students in R tutorial sections and led discussions in American politics class.
- Mentored 20+ undergraduate students on semester-long R research projects.

**DATA ANALYTICS INTERN** 

JUN 2022 — AUG 2022

Hanover Research

Arlington, Virginia

- Created statistical models to analyze factors that influence students' academic outcomes and graduate rates.
- Reviewed formatting and data accuracy in key client deliverables, such as Tableau dashboards and reports.
- Worked with Research Associates and Content Analysts to collect information for use in reports and determine the scope of work for clients.

JUNIOR RESEARCHER JUN 2018 — AUG 2018

European Institute for Asian Studies

Brussels, Belgium

- Utilized existing data set to co-author a quantitative report on Taiwanese foreign investment in the European Union, commissioned by the Taiwanese Representative Office in Belgium and the EU to promote Taiwan-EU trade.
- Provided operational support to event organization (workshops and briefing seminars).
- · Participated in conferences and seminars organized by think tanks (Bruegel), the European Parliament, and embassies.

# **ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICER (INTERN)**

JUN 2017 — AUG 2017

Home Affairs Department of Hong Kong SAR Government

Hong Kong SAR

- Conducted a qualitative comparative study on homeless policy in Canada, Denmark, Hong Kong, Singapore, U.K., and U.S.
- Refined the Facebook page of the Sham Shui Po Youth Corps by providing recommendations to the District Officer.
- · Participated in the District Council meetings and the public administration of the HKSAR.

SUMMER INTERN JUN 2016 — AUG 2016

The European Chamber of Commerce in Hong Kong

Hong Kong SAR

- Conducted research on financial technology policies and automotive industry, particularly in Hong Kong and the European Union, for the Business Councils' position papers
- Assembled a report on electric vehicles in Hong Kong for the bilateral negotiation between the EU and HK govt (report presented to the Financial Secretary of Hong Kong and led to the reconsideration of EV subsidies).
- Partnered with and interviewed major automotive manufacturers, fintech, and law firms as part of the research.

## **EDUCATION**

| Doctor of Philosophy in Political Science, George Washington University                      | May 2024 (expected) |
|--|---------------------|
| Master of Arts in Political Science, George Washington University                            | 2022                |
| Summer Program in Quantitative Methods of Social Research, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor | 2021                |
| Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, Politics and Economics, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor    | 2018                |

## **PRESENTATIONS**

| American Political Science Association Annual Meeting     | 2022 (declined) |
|---|-----------------|
| Asian Politics Online Seminar Series                      | 2021            |
| Northeastern Political Science Association Annual Meeting | 2021            |
| Midwest Political Science Association Annual Meeting      | 2021, 2022      |
| Western Political Science Association Annual Meeting      | 2021            |